<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Travel, Tech, and Experience Dairies</description>
    <link>
    https://shubhamdp.github.io</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Ashtavinayak pilgrimage on bike</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;637 km, 8 places, 2 days, and 1 Yamaha FZs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/ashtavinayak-pilgrimage-on-bike</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/ashtavinayak-pilgrimage-on-bike</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Time Machine</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;On weekends, I prefer wandering the outskirts of the city, staring at the sunset, sunrises, cool skies. But in these difficult times, it’s kinda impossible. So, I use this “time machine”, &lt;strong&gt;Google Photos&lt;/strong&gt;, to take a dig down the memory lane, relieving the sunsets, sunrises, the woods in the outskirts of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/time-machine</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/time-machine</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Paper Towns</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Quentin, Q, lives across the street to Margo. He is infatuated with her since she moved into the neighborhood. They used to play together in their childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/paper-towns</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/paper-towns</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Me Before You</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Me Before You&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/me-before-you</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/me-before-you</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money is plentiful for those who understand the simple rules of its acquisition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s-clason</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s-clason</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Notebook(Movie)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;‘The Notebook’ is a romantic drama based on the novel ‘The Notebook’ by Nicolas Sparks. Noah is played by Ryan Gosling and Allie by Rachel McAdams. The Movie starts with an elderly man at old age home, he reads a love story to his fellow patient who has lost her memory.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/the-notebookmovie</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/the-notebookmovie</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>My journey to Harishchandragad</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We planned, packed our bags and en routed to Pachnai, one of the base villages to reach the top of Harishchandragad . Harishchandragad is one of the well known forts for camping in Ahmadnagar district. Harishchandragad is situated at 1422 meters from sea level. One can reach Harishchandragad top via three routes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/my-journey-to-harishchandragad</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/my-journey-to-harishchandragad</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Pari</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;“Go back home”, Saboor shouting at Abdull. Saboor and Pari, his daughter, were on their way to Kabul. Abdull was very close to his 3 years old sister. After all, he was the one who was looking after her since their mother passed away a year ago. Their stepmother was busy looking after her kids. Abdull was 10. Saboor started throwing stones at Abdull, but he was dodging it and did not give up. Finally, he convinced his father and joined them on the journey to Kabul. The journey would take 2 days by foot from Shahbagh. They rested near a cave that night and had dinner. Next day early morning they were moving. Nabi, Saboor’s brother-in-law, was waiting for them near the Kabul’s shoe market. He took them to his owner’s house. Saboor married Nabi’s sister after his first wife died due to typhoid.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/pari</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/pari</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Walk to Remember</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Love story by Nicolas Sparks which unfolds gradually.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/a-walk-to-remember</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/a-walk-to-remember</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Magic Potion</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There lived a man named Aayub in a village named Gul Daman. He was very hard working. He married a beautiful woman named Mariam and they were blessed with 3 boys and 2 girls. Out of the five children, he was very fond of the youngest one, Qais. Everything was fantastic, but as the day follows night, Aayub’s bad time was close.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/magic-potion</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/magic-potion</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Google's way of feeding captcha</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;You and your friends make a plan to travel by train. You open Google Chrome and enter www.irctc.co.in. You fill in the user name, password and an extra field which challenges you to identify random alphanumeric characters. This extra verification field is called as captcha, this is intended to avoid automated machine logins. It is a way to distinguish human and machine inputs, this helps to prevent spam and automated data extraction from websites.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://shubhamdp.github.io/googles-way-of-feeding-captcha</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shubhamdp.github.io/googles-way-of-feeding-captcha</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
