<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/book/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-10-02T06:54:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/book/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Nomad | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Travel, Tech, and Experience Dairies</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Paper Towns</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/paper-towns" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper Towns" />
      <published>2020-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/paper-towns</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/paper-towns">&lt;p&gt;Quentin, Q, lives across the street to Margo. He is infatuated with her since she moved into the neighborhood. They used to play together in their childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One fine evening, Q and Margo were headed to Jefferson Park riding a bicycle. They were blown by a dead body attached to the tree. When Q took two steps back, at the same time she moved two steps forward. This shows Q was shit scared and Margo a brave girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night Margo climbs Q’s window and told him about her findings after a day-long investigation regarding the dead body. Rather focusing on her words he was innocently staring at her beautiful face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life goes on, school, home, blah blah blah… but his crush remained constant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margo was a cool kid who planned pranks on/with friends, likes to roam around. Along with friends, she once wrapped the neighborhood with toilet paper. Do you feel the intensity of how adventurous is she?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Q was the silent, unassertive guy. He liked to play Resurrection along with his friends Ben (“Benjamin”) and Radar (“Marcus”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly after nine years, Margo again climbs through the same window and takes Q with her on an adventure. Q did not know that this night is gonna change him, the way he thinks about her, the way he looked at life. He was going to do a shit load of adventurous stuff. She had planned eleven pranks which they will be pulling on her friends. She wanted to take revenge from her ex-boyfriend and best-friend who cheated on her. They carried eight of her pranks. Then she asked Q if he had someone in mind with whom they can pull the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These pranks were mostly breaking and entering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the tenth, they enter the highest building in the Town. They stare at the town from the top of the building, view is just amazing. She calls this view a paper town and says “Things look beautiful from the distance, but when we get close to it looks worst”. She relates this to herself like how her friends are drifting away as they are getting to know her better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they leave for the last one, to break into the SeaWorld.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time in the lifetime Q has spent such a bold night. He thinks that he may spend time with her from tomorrow. He builds the thoughts on what to speak with her when she arrives and many more. But she did not show up at the school. She goes missing.  She left the home. This is not the first time she left home without informing anyone. But she always left a clue where she was going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even this time she left the clues. This time she left the trail of clues for Quentin. Can he prove his love by finding her?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will he be able to solve the clues, the treasure hunt? What if these clues take him to the dead ends? Even if he finds her, does she really left the clues for him? Can he convince her to come back?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, why did she even left?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of unknowns, but I would say, written like a drama, but filled with mystery, a boy on an adventure to find his girl and to get answers to a few questions!!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="book" />
      
        <category term="story" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Quentin, Q, lives across the street to Margo. He is infatuated with her since she moved into the neighborhood. They used to play together in their childhood.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Me Before You</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/me-before-you" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Me Before You" />
      <published>2020-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/me-before-you</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/me-before-you">&lt;p&gt;Me Before You&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had nothing in common until love gave them everything to lose…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louisa Clark knows how many steps are there between her home and the bus stop. The chatty girl works at Buttered Bun Cafe. She could suggest you the perfect calorie count cupcake. An ordinary girl living an exceedingly ordinary life. Steady boyfriend, close family, who has barely been farther than their tiny village. She takes a badly needed job working for Will Traynor, who is wheelchair bound after an accident. Will has always lived a huge life, big deals, extreme sports, worldwide travel and now he’s pretty sure he cannot live the way he is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will is acerbic, moody, bossy, but Lou refuses to treat him with kid gloves, and soon his happiness means more to her than she expected. When she learns that Will has shocking plans of his own, she sets out to show him that life is still worth living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They start spending time together. They make fun of each other, talks witty. She shaves his beard and trims his hair. Cleaned shaved Will looks handsome. If it wouldn’t have been a wheelchair there would be ton of girls stalking him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lou plans an outing at racecourse along with Nathan but this fails miserably. Will and Lou attends a musical concert where She dresses in the perfect red gown and man she looks staggeringly beautiful. Anyone will be dumbfounded and Will is not an exception. Lou even accompanies Will to Alicia’s wedding. They both enjoy the music and drinks and guess what, when everyone starts to dance, Lou asks Will to give her a whirl. She sits in his lap and Will moves his chair towards the dance floor and he gives a whirl. Everyone gets surprised, even Alicia. These are the best days of Will since his accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book made me fall in love with Louisa. Its a life of two people who couldn’t have less in common, a heart breaking romantic novel that asks, What do you do when making the person you love happy also means breaking your own heart?&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="book" />
      
        <category term="story" />
      
        <category term="romance" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Me Before You</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s-clason" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason" />
      <published>2019-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s-clason</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/the-richest-man-in-babylon-by-george-s-clason">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money is plentiful for those who understand the simple rules of its acquisition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoiler below, if you are keen about reading the book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1052.The_Richest_Man_in_Babylon&quot;&gt;read more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-the-basics-cleared&quot;&gt;Get the basics cleared&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part of all you earn is yours to keep&lt;/em&gt;,  pay yourself first. It should not be less than one-tenth of your earning no matter how little you earn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do take advice but from the ones who know about it. (eg: about brickmaking take advice from brickman)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investment will make babies and you will also want babies should make babies. So do not waste the returns reinvest them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seven-cures-for-lean-purse&quot;&gt;Seven Cures for Lean Purse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Start your purse to fattening&lt;/em&gt; Pay yourself at least one-tenth of your earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Control your expenditure&lt;/em&gt; Budget your expenses that you may have to pay for necessities, enjoyment, and desires without spending more than nine-tenths of your earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make your money multiply&lt;/em&gt; Reinvest the returns. Put your money to labor so that it may reproduce its kind and add it to income. A stream of wealth shall flow constantly into your purse.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guard the treasure against loss Better a little caution than a great regret&lt;/em&gt;. Invest in only places where the principal is safe, where it may be reclaimed and where you may not fail to collect the rental. Consult a wise man, let the wisdom guard your treasure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make of your dwelling a profitable investment&lt;/em&gt; Own your own home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ensure a future income&lt;/em&gt; Prepare for a suitable income in the days to come. Provide in advance for the needs of your growing age and the protection of your family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Increase the ability to earn&lt;/em&gt; Cultivate your power and become wiser, to become more skillful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-man-in-debt&quot;&gt;For Man in debt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where the determination is, way can be found&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay yourself one-tenth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to live on seven-tenths&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep two-tenth for the clearing debt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="book" />
      
        <category term="finance" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Money is plentiful for those who understand the simple rules of its acquisition</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Pari</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/pari" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pari" />
      <published>2019-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/pari</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/pari">&lt;p&gt;“Go back home”, Saboor shouting at Abdull. Saboor and Pari, his daughter, were on their way to Kabul. Abdull was very close to his 3 years old sister. After all, he was the one who was looking after her since their mother passed away a year ago. Their stepmother was busy looking after her kids. Abdull was 10. Saboor started throwing stones at Abdull, but he was dodging it and did not give up. Finally, he convinced his father and joined them on the journey to Kabul. The journey would take 2 days by foot from Shahbagh. They rested near a cave that night and had dinner. Next day early morning they were moving. Nabi, Saboor’s brother-in-law, was waiting for them near the Kabul’s shoe market. He took them to his owner’s house. Saboor married Nabi’s sister after his first wife died due to typhoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. and Mrs. Wahdati, owners were having trouble conceiving a child. A few days ago Mrs. Wahdati asked Nabi to take her to Shahbagh. There he introduced her to his sister’s family. Saboor used to work on construction site on daily wages. But the war between the Afghan government and the Mujahideen took away his family’s bread and butter. He was having a difficult time finding a new job. Mrs. Wahdati was enchanted by the cute Pari. Nabi noticed how she was interacting with little Pari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back Mrs. Wahdati was sobbing in the backseat. Nabi felt bad, he knew the reasons. When they arrived in Kabul, Nabi suggested them to buy Pari, he said he would talk with Saboor. They thought about it and agreed. Saboor was struggling to find employment so he agreed to it. To feed the family he decided to sacrifice Pari. Saboor knew the intensity of the bond between Pari and Abdull, that’s why he was hesitating to take Abdull with him. He knew that Abdull would be alone without Pari. But considering that this would be the last few moments he would be spending with Pari, he agreed to take him to Kabul. 20 years later…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abdull was blessed with a girl child. How could he not name her Pari? He told the story of selling Pari to his wife and Pari. Pari used to look at other children in her neighborhood who had siblings to play with. So, Pari considered that she has a twin sister Pari, who looked exactly like her. Pari’s sister was present everywhere with her. She was only visible to her. Abdull used to tell her bedtime story and when he left the room thinking she is asleep, she used to put on an extra pillow beside her pillow and go to sleep saying goodbye to her twin sister Pari. Her bond with Pari was out of the world, that no body could understand, not even Abdull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-————-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is extracted from ‘And the mountains echoed’ novel by Khaled Hosseini. Back in 1950’s, due to extreme poverty in Afghanistan, poor families were selling their kids to rich families. Unknowingly kids were sacrificed to feed the remaining family. This was good for the kid’s future, they would grow in better environment, good food, education rather than struggling for daily wages.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="story" />
      
        <category term="book" />
      
        <category term="novel" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">“Go back home”, Saboor shouting at Abdull. Saboor and Pari, his daughter, were on their way to Kabul. Abdull was very close to his 3 years old sister. After all, he was the one who was looking after her since their mother passed away a year ago. Their stepmother was busy looking after her kids. Abdull was 10. Saboor started throwing stones at Abdull, but he was dodging it and did not give up. Finally, he convinced his father and joined them on the journey to Kabul. The journey would take 2 days by foot from Shahbagh. They rested near a cave that night and had dinner. Next day early morning they were moving. Nabi, Saboor’s brother-in-law, was waiting for them near the Kabul’s shoe market. He took them to his owner’s house. Saboor married Nabi’s sister after his first wife died due to typhoid.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Walk to Remember</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/a-walk-to-remember" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Walk to Remember" />
      <published>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/a-walk-to-remember</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/a-walk-to-remember">&lt;p&gt;Love story by Nicolas Sparks which unfolds gradually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landon Carter, son of a congressman, is a High School student at Beaufort High, Beaufort, North Carolina. As a congressman, Landon’s father spends most of his time away from the family. Jamie, daughter of a minister in the church at Beaufort, loves to do social work, she is actively involved in social activities in town. She carries the Bible with her and according to her, whatever happens is a Lord’s Plan. Both Jamie and Landon attends the same school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landon gets elected as the President at school. Landon always tries to avoid Jamie. But when Landon do not find a date for school’s annual function, without any choice he asks Jamie. To return the favor he has to enact in Christmas play in lead role. The play is very close to Jamie since it was written by her father and he who has started this tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie and Landon with others rehearse the play every day. After a week, Jamie asks Landon to walk her home and it becomes routine. Landon started to like Jamie. On regular days Jamie wears a brown sweater and tie her hair in a bun. On the play day, she unveils her beautiful white angelic costume and hair untied. Her angelic looks made Landon fall in love with her. Even on that day, he walks her home. After a few days, he confesses his love to her, Jamie has a surprise which shocks Landon and he realizes what fate has handed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story well organized, every chapter tends you to read the next one and of course filled with love.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="romance" />
      
        <category term="book" />
      
        <category term="story" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Love story by Nicolas Sparks which unfolds gradually.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Magic Potion</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/magic-potion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Magic Potion" />
      <published>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/magic-potion</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/magic-potion">&lt;p&gt;There lived a man named Aayub in a village named Gul Daman. He was very hard working. He married a beautiful woman named Mariam and they were blessed with 3 boys and 2 girls. Out of the five children, he was very fond of the youngest one, Qais. Everything was fantastic, but as the day follows night, Aayub’s bad time was close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a demon, A monstrous one, who used to visit villages and take away a child from each village. Sadly, he caught Aayub and Aayub had to decide whether he wanted to give one of his children or if he fights the demon he would lose all five. He has time till morning. Then after discussing this with his wife they agreed on drawing a chit. Unlucky for Aayub, Qais was the word on the drawn chit. With a heavy heart he called Qais. Qais had no idea what was going on. He jumped happily towards Aayub. He took Qais outside the home and left him there and closed the door. Qais banged the door with all the force he could gather. Aayub cried helplessly. The demon appeared and took Qais far away towards the mountains where nobody would dare visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aayub, his wife and kids were in agony. Everyone back in the village named Aayub a coward. Even he thought the same, but his wife consoled him. Aayub, tired of hearing bad words from villagers, decided to fight the demon. He packed his dagger, food for his trip and started walking towards the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aayub had decided to walk the tough journey, he did not even know where and how far the demon lived how many days WOULD his food last. But finally, he made it. He started throwing stones at the demon’s door. The demon asked him why was he there? He said that he came to take his son back home. The demon asked him to enter the room. With no choice left, he followed the demon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demon drew the curtain and on a glass wall, Aayub could see his son. Qais seemed happy, he was playing with a few other kids. Aayub shouted with his name but it was of no use, Qais was unaware of the things on the other side of the glass. The demon gave some time to Aayub and asked him to decide whether he wanted to see HIS son happy, get well educated or take him with back to the village. He was again at the hot seat. After thinking for a while and looking at his son for the last time, he started walking towards home. The demon said that he had made the right choice, but only a father would know a loss of the son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demon handed Aayub a magic potion and told to drink it on the route back home. When he returned he was questioned about Qais by everyone in his, but he did not seem to remember anything, about his meeting with demon or Qais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There on he lived happily without even a thought of Qais, sighed happily, listened to the wind sweeping down from the mountains, to the chirping of the night birds. All thanks to the magic potion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the summary of a bedtime story narrated by father to his son and daughter from a book ‘And the Mountains Echoed’ by Khaled Hosseini. Few of the names are not as same as they are in the book.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="story" />
      
        <category term="book" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">There lived a man named Aayub in a village named Gul Daman. He was very hard working. He married a beautiful woman named Mariam and they were blessed with 3 boys and 2 girls. Out of the five children, he was very fond of the youngest one, Qais. Everything was fantastic, but as the day follows night, Aayub’s bad time was close.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
