<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/writing/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-10-02T06:54:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/writing/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Nomad | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Travel, Tech, and Experience Dairies</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Time Machine</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/time-machine" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time Machine" />
      <published>2020-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/time-machine</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/time-machine">&lt;p&gt;On weekends, I prefer wandering the outskirts of the city, staring at the sunset, sunrises, cool skies. But in these difficult times, it’s kinda impossible. So, I use this “time machine”, &lt;strong&gt;Google Photos&lt;/strong&gt;, to take a dig down the memory lane, relieving the sunsets, sunrises, the woods in the outskirts of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes lost on the bicycle try to find the way home, I only remember the moments in journey, I never really cared about thet destination. Cause I have to make it to the home anyway 😜.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memories made, the laughter, the giggles, the fun, oh how can one forget the adventure. Little breakthroughs, its celebrations, sad moments, setbacks(though we hardly capture the sad moments).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staring at the photo and remembering the story that picture is telling you. Still scrolling down the photos going back in time, a year back, 2 years back, and so on till you hit the bottom of few thousand photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every picture or set of pictures tells a story. It has the prologue, the main story, and the epilogue. Sorry for the bookish description, FYI, I don’t read a lot. Since its not a dream you do remember how you came to that place. By the way, in dreams you do not remember how you enter the place. The conversation you had or the breathtaking scenery you enjoyed or the incidents occurred, memories created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know what you just did, you relived the moment in your past. You took yourself back in time, had the same conversation, or relished the moment and came back to normal time. I hope you were smiling or blushing when you were in there or enjoying the cool breeze on your face or the raindrops thrashing your face when you were hiking in rain. A late-night walk and talk with the close friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, if I have to describe it, I would say I just experienced time travel. Although, I could not correct the mistakes I have made in the past, or change things the way I want to. But why to regret it, because you wanted it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theodore Roosevelt once said, “I am part of everything I read.” So these are your pictures, your memories and you were part of it. Sorry, you still are part of it. Since you have time in this lockdown, take a moment and relive it, AGAIN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Google Photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Home, Stay Safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;image-gallary&quot;&gt;Image Gallary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;subscribe-form&quot;&gt;
    &lt;style&gt;
  .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
  .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
  .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
  .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  

  
    

      
      

      &lt;a href=&quot;/burrrp/assets/images/time-machine/Sunrise from Sinhgad Fort.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sunrise from Sinhgad Fort&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp//assets/images/time-machine/Sunrise from Sinhgad Fort.jpg&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;fit=cover&amp;amp;mask=ellipse&amp;amp;mtrim&amp;amp;mbg=f4f8fb&quot; alt=&quot;Sunrise from Sinhgad Fort&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;Sunrise from Sinhgad Fort&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  

  
    

      
      

      &lt;a href=&quot;/burrrp/assets/images/time-machine/Sunset from Arambol hill.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sunset from Arambol hill&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp//assets/images/time-machine/Sunset from Arambol hill.jpg&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;fit=cover&amp;amp;mask=ellipse&amp;amp;mtrim&amp;amp;mbg=f4f8fb&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset from Arambol hill&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;Sunset from Arambol hill&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  

  

  

  

  

  

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="writing" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">On weekends, I prefer wandering the outskirts of the city, staring at the sunset, sunrises, cool skies. But in these difficult times, it’s kinda impossible. So, I use this “time machine”, Google Photos, to take a dig down the memory lane, relieving the sunsets, sunrises, the woods in the outskirts of the city.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
