<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/movie/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-10-02T06:54:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/movie/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Nomad | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Travel, Tech, and Experience Dairies</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Notebook(Movie)</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/the-notebookmovie" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Notebook(Movie)" />
      <published>2019-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/the-notebookmovie</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/the-notebookmovie">&lt;p&gt;‘The Notebook’ is a romantic drama based on the novel ‘The Notebook’ by Nicolas Sparks. Noah is played by Ryan Gosling and Allie by Rachel McAdams. The Movie starts with an elderly man at old age home, he reads a love story to his fellow patient who has lost her memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Will you dance with me?”, Noah asks Allie when he sees her at the fair for the very first time. “No” from Allie could not stop him from trying one more time. When Noah attempts a daredevil stunt of hanging to ferry wheel, she agrees to go out with him. She says just to escape from the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fin’s girlfriend, Sarah, is a good friend of Allie. Fin is Noah’s friend at work. Fin and Sarah invite Allie to the movie and she did not expect to see Noah there. After the movie Fin and Sarah take a car ride home. Noah and Allie decide to walk and there you go….another love story started with a walk !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noah is the laborer at Lumberyard, a sawmill, and Allie is a rich kid. Allie was enjoying something different from her daily routine, she was having fun with Noah. They were really enjoying the good time until Allie’s family thinks of an intervention. They move to New York for Allie’s higher studies. Noah, for a year, writes to Allie every single day and Allie’s mother make sure that those letters do not reach Allie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Noah and Fin join the Army to serve in World War II. Allie pursues her nursing and serves in a hospital filled with soldiers injured in war. There she met a wounded soldier, Lon, who asks her out. Lon and Allie fall in love and after spending some time together they decide to get married. After Returning from the war, Noah starts to build the house of his dreams. Few days before the wedding Allie sees a photograph of Noah with the house in a newspaper and she decides to meet him by seeking permission from Lon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story of young love, separation, another love, and dilemma. I liked the movie, do give it a try to know what happens further, whether Allie chooses Lon or Noah.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="movie" />
      
        <category term="story" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">‘The Notebook’ is a romantic drama based on the novel ‘The Notebook’ by Nicolas Sparks. Noah is played by Ryan Gosling and Allie by Rachel McAdams. The Movie starts with an elderly man at old age home, he reads a love story to his fellow patient who has lost her memory.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
