<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/romance/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-10-02T06:54:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/tag/romance/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Nomad | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Travel, Tech, and Experience Dairies</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Me Before You</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/me-before-you" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Me Before You" />
      <published>2020-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/me-before-you</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/me-before-you">&lt;p&gt;Me Before You&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had nothing in common until love gave them everything to lose…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louisa Clark knows how many steps are there between her home and the bus stop. The chatty girl works at Buttered Bun Cafe. She could suggest you the perfect calorie count cupcake. An ordinary girl living an exceedingly ordinary life. Steady boyfriend, close family, who has barely been farther than their tiny village. She takes a badly needed job working for Will Traynor, who is wheelchair bound after an accident. Will has always lived a huge life, big deals, extreme sports, worldwide travel and now he’s pretty sure he cannot live the way he is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will is acerbic, moody, bossy, but Lou refuses to treat him with kid gloves, and soon his happiness means more to her than she expected. When she learns that Will has shocking plans of his own, she sets out to show him that life is still worth living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They start spending time together. They make fun of each other, talks witty. She shaves his beard and trims his hair. Cleaned shaved Will looks handsome. If it wouldn’t have been a wheelchair there would be ton of girls stalking him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lou plans an outing at racecourse along with Nathan but this fails miserably. Will and Lou attends a musical concert where She dresses in the perfect red gown and man she looks staggeringly beautiful. Anyone will be dumbfounded and Will is not an exception. Lou even accompanies Will to Alicia’s wedding. They both enjoy the music and drinks and guess what, when everyone starts to dance, Lou asks Will to give her a whirl. She sits in his lap and Will moves his chair towards the dance floor and he gives a whirl. Everyone gets surprised, even Alicia. These are the best days of Will since his accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book made me fall in love with Louisa. Its a life of two people who couldn’t have less in common, a heart breaking romantic novel that asks, What do you do when making the person you love happy also means breaking your own heart?&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="book" />
      
        <category term="story" />
      
        <category term="romance" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Me Before You</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Walk to Remember</title>
      <link href="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/a-walk-to-remember" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Walk to Remember" />
      <published>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/a-walk-to-remember</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://shubhamdp.github.io/burrrp/a-walk-to-remember">&lt;p&gt;Love story by Nicolas Sparks which unfolds gradually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landon Carter, son of a congressman, is a High School student at Beaufort High, Beaufort, North Carolina. As a congressman, Landon’s father spends most of his time away from the family. Jamie, daughter of a minister in the church at Beaufort, loves to do social work, she is actively involved in social activities in town. She carries the Bible with her and according to her, whatever happens is a Lord’s Plan. Both Jamie and Landon attends the same school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landon gets elected as the President at school. Landon always tries to avoid Jamie. But when Landon do not find a date for school’s annual function, without any choice he asks Jamie. To return the favor he has to enact in Christmas play in lead role. The play is very close to Jamie since it was written by her father and he who has started this tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie and Landon with others rehearse the play every day. After a week, Jamie asks Landon to walk her home and it becomes routine. Landon started to like Jamie. On regular days Jamie wears a brown sweater and tie her hair in a bun. On the play day, she unveils her beautiful white angelic costume and hair untied. Her angelic looks made Landon fall in love with her. Even on that day, he walks her home. After a few days, he confesses his love to her, Jamie has a surprise which shocks Landon and he realizes what fate has handed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story well organized, every chapter tends you to read the next one and of course filled with love.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Shubham Patil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="romance" />
      
        <category term="book" />
      
        <category term="story" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Love story by Nicolas Sparks which unfolds gradually.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
